[Music]
hello and welcome to the junkyard
what is Bracken my bros welcome to the
podcast right before we get going you
know I'd love to give some
recommendations in the form of TED Talks
or books or podcasts that might enhance
your life in some sort of way and
knowledge is power so I'm gonna go with
Mark Manson's two books two-for-one
special we've got mark Manson's
the subtle art of not giving an F
hardcover as a bright orange cover
really catches your eye and the second
one is a bright teal color and that is
everything is EFT Shaylee just finished
the first one so she it's fresh on my
brain and I finished the last one when
he came out with it
they're both great books for people who
perhaps don't read a ton maybe reading
like the wording and reading is a bit
complicated and over wordy he writes
kind of laid-back and sarcastically so
check those out
mark manson subtle art of not giving
enough and everything is eft he also has
a a weekly newsletter and a blog check
those out looks good to the pod cars
okay so I think that at the beginning we
should introduce you as the rap name
that you mentioned earlier and the rap
name that I remember from high school
what is it what was your rap name no I
don't vote her out
I don't remember my rap name I feel like
you've had it was it like GMAC fizzle or
something or like max whistle it seems
like there was a fizzle in this maybe I
felt like people call me every like
anything call me like thorn porn
no that wasn't my rap name I don't
remember you Mac torn that's another
name that's not really a Mac that's kind
of like a hard rap name if you needed to
Mac Mac cuz I gear I met you know return
of the Mac your
Mack and then you gotta throw in the
bridge story just torn yeah let's start
there McKenzie
oh we're recording yeah we're recording
alright we'll loop back into it
hey do you ever speaking of recording
I'm cutting a little bit
speaking of recording raps do you ever
hop on like the PA before and before you
do you ever do the safety thing yourself
so it depends on the plane you're on so
if you're on a plane without the screens
and the movie is available to you so
that plays a safety demo so those are
mostly planes I fly out of Seattle out
of New York there would be like the MD
97 1:7 those planes don't have the
screen so you'd have to go out in the
aisle does it make you nervous no I'm so
used to it now but it's kind of weird
just most people are on their phones
like honestly when you get on the plane
do you really pay attention to the
safety demo no I don't see I have this
thing where I try to act like I try to
act like I've heard it so many times
because I fly all the time
but I think that realist I do actually
have this thought cross my mind like
okay suddenly we do go down I think that
I would be like looking around at like
okay what am i [__] to you again I
think that no matter how much we think I
mean in realistic like I sent you the
other day if we go down
I mean we're gonna like it's gonna be we
can put our head between our laps but
we're gonna just be cut up by metal and
the sharing Jesus we're supposed to say
optimistic but you got in training when
we're getting trained on like ditching
in the ocean I'm just sitting there like
what like be realistic with her yeah
they're teaching us how to load their
rafts and which is great I mean but I'm
like man if we hit that ocean I'm sorry
like going down I'm so fast yes like
when you see it when you see it in movie
they do it I feel like they do a pretty
good job because I'll just have like
that just solid camera inside the cabin
yeah and then all of a sudden would be
like silent and then they hit it and
just water rushes through the is I mean
like just being realistic
but so like the movie is solely that was
just like once-in-a-lifetime where they
landed on the Hudson you know and they
got everyone out that was because they
just took off and there's a bird strike
and you could they weren't high enough
they just taken off so they're low
enough to just do a nice landing I mean
if you're
35,000 feet in there and like caterer
going down the Pacific Ocean it's like
yeah we're [__] okay okay so if say
that you were they may have even told
you this like how long is it on your
typical like we're going down how long
is it before you hit the would it be
like 45 minutes of like you trying not
to crash but you probably would after
for a minute it honestly just depends on
what's wrong it depends on the type of
emergency if they're I mean if there's
fires if the engine goes out there's two
backup engines on every plane just so
everyone knows I didn't know that yeah
so if one engine goes out but usually
they'll still land the plane anyway just
cuz it's not good for the plane yeah but
yeah it depends if there's a
decompression which means the oxygen
masks are going to go down and the door
that means there's like a leak and air
is coming in the cabin okay so it
depends on that like if something like
that happens you can just go straight
down yeah it all depends yeah because it
can get bad so fast I think I know I
guess I just think I've obviously in
movies but like when like one airplane
window breaks and then everything in the
plane obviously goes to hell yeah of
course just a little bit of a small hole
yeah it would just depend on what's
going on with that a lot of the time
yeah I had a yellow emergency there's
different types red a severe but they
called us and said our brake system went
out and so we had to lay on the plane
with a brake system and so that kind of
made me nervous but even when things
like that happen I feel they're like
they're prepared for it right yeah
they've run every I mean it's such an
intense thing we're sitting in a chair
in the sky yeah it's pretty insane I
feel like we definitely have it down
before we just let people play for
tickets up there right and like you and
I talked about the other night
how people complain it was about stuff
on the plane but it's like we're in this
metal tube oh my god this guy flying
like it's just crazy to me yeah people
get so caught up in they're like in
there I mean entitlement look for lack
of a better word I guess but just like
you use PC it a lot in customer service
but I feel like you probably see it
fairly often you know because people are
pretty high nerves a lot of times people
are traveling they're stressed you know
regardless of what they're doing if
you're vacationing or you're going for
work
it's like stressful to fly so like you
probably get kind of in the [__] side
of people often too a lot of the time
yeah not every flight it's crazy
New York to LA is a really hard flight
for me to work because everyone's so
entitled it's just two big cities yeah
everyone's complaining about everything
I feel like and so when I was based in
New York everyone would want to do those
flights because celebrities are on them
it's a huge market they look people live
in New York and they fly down to LA to
shoot a movie and so but I I started
working on my mic ever no one's in a
good mood I'm just like no one's happy
on these flights and so I like doing
flights so like Kansas City everyone's
nice like everyone just like how are you
how's your day I think I think I find it
do you for fly it's like any small
airports like there's so many that are
just like these like there's like four
terminals yeah like Kansas City is one
of those that's super super small
Missouri oh no I think I have flown out
of there I think uh yeah I think that's
one is it I think that's one they also
have the airplanes there's a lot of
airplanes in airports that have these
but they have airplanes inside the yeah
yeah I like flying like Bozeman Montana
there's Billings Montana like places
like that the airports are huge so
they're just different kinds of people
and then people are nice and seems like
yeah they're way nicer I know it sounds
crazy but just from my experience
working on those flights and being based
out of New York there was such a culture
shock going back to Seattle because in
New York I could stand at the boarding
door and be like hi welcome and I'd be
smiling and they just look you up and
down they don't say anything that's just
so weird yeah that's just a New Yorker
and so you get used to it and then when
I came to Seattle people are like good
morning and how are you I'm so happy to
be here and I'm like wow okay you
definitely noticed the difference yeah
flying around okay so back up give me or
you are stationed so you primarily work
out of Seattle now you're stationed out
of Seattle you'll have to explain how
that it works but before you were
stationed out of New York station is
that even the correct terminology you
could say that base base out of New York
yeah okay so when you when you first
started out how long you been apply it
to it for years
smart well that's crazy it seems like it
doesn't seem like it'd be that long but
okay well I gotta go guys the podcast we
have a good day drink some water take
care of yourself yeah so when I first
got out of training nothing on the west
coast was open so they had basically
meaning they had enough flight
attendants in those bases for the amount
of flights going out each day so my
choices were Minneapolis Boston Detroit
in New York and none of the other ones
really appealed to me I was like alright
I'm gonna go back yeah go big or go home
I'm gonna go to New York and I'm really
glad I did it
it was a really cool experience but
you're in charge of three airports there
so I think that's part of the reason why
the base is kind of open and it's more
junior Seattle you have to just worry
about driving to that one Airport but in
New York its LaGuardia JFK and Newark so
they could call you and be like hey in
three hours you need to work this flight
in New Jersey and it takes like two
hours to get there so it's things like
that I feel like the more senior people
want to be at a base with one Airport
yeah did you when you when you first
started when you first like had your
desire to even made me look into being a
flight attendant is that where you
wanted to be working for this company in
New York well well well for for Delta I
was never a plan okay it was kind of
weird how it happened so a lot of you
probably know Keela more we went to high
school with her it was her dream to be a
flight attendant and so when she got the
job she would message me and just like
you should really apply you travel all
the time even I used to be kind of
scared of flying so when she was telling
me that I was like like I don't know I
have to have three bears to even get on
the flight every day before works all
right guys yeah I remember one time I
was flying and it was like really bad
turbulence going to Hawaii and I was
like god I was like praying and I see
I'll never get on another plane again
like I was so scared so those thoughts
were like running through my mind I'm
like realistically I don't know if I can
do this you know I'm so scared of flying
as is
um and then she kept messaging me and I
remember I was on a flight back from
Arizona and going back to Seattle and I
was like I spent all my money on plane
tickets like she's right and so I
randomly it wasn't like I was looking
for any certain companies she was
working for Delta and so she's like I'll
refer you like just apply and so at that
point I was like okay I'm just I'm gonna
do it I'm gonna randomly apply not
knowing or thinking that I would
actually get it because it's so
competitive and then yeah I ended up
getting it was a really quick process
and they flew me out to Atlanta for the
last interview and there there was like
80 people in the interview and so when I
got there I kind of just told myself be
relaxed like you know this is just let's
just see what how it's gonna go and
everyone was so nervous I didn't realize
how competitive it really was and so I
kind of told myself in the beginning if
you don't get this like it's not a big
deal to so many other people are gonna
walk away and go home without getting it
and yeah I ended up getting it it was
just a really cool experience and yeah
it all kind of just happened I'm like
well I'm doing it so well it's a cool
dream that still like came true it's
like you get locked onto it and it's
cool that you have like friends who work
for the same company - yeah Kyle acutely
does - and she grew up in Longview so
it's kind of cool three of us right now
I do you know do you work with people
are people just from all over do you
know people from just different yeah um
people commute from everywhere
so like when I was based in New York for
a while I was living with the goth
hearts and so I had a place in
Washington and then the day before I
would have to work out flight in New
York and some of the time so people I
know people that have commuted to New
York from London like they live in
London and then they'll fly in to New
York to work and then they go back after
I mean that seems so crazy but like if
you could make it at work that's
actually super cool yeah if you get free
flight so yeah people are from all over
and you meet so many cool people every
time I work so every week I have like a
three day trip I'm always meeting
someone new I'm not real always and then
Seattle's kind of a small base so
you get to know the people there so my
trips now I normally at least know one
person on my trip so it's kind of cool
that's nice it's not like a completely
new group of strangers every time yeah
but everyone for the most part everyone
gets along like of course at every job
there's some people who just don't click
with but everyone's just really nice I
don't know I've met so many great
friends through this job yeah ok so what
are what are the other perks of being a
flattened obviously there's like because
at the beginning it's just like oh my
god I want to travel around the world
and like you fly it at it perfect yeah
but you know I'm sure there's like a lot
of a lot of different things that came
up or different things different places
you didn't expect to go to you've told
me about this place I definitely want to
talk about that to the like this island
somewhere
was it Iceland Thailand oh it was a
place in Thailand it was like you party
all night or something
oh yeah he's over there breaking is my
cake no just punching people in the ear
if they're in their car they just got
something for you yeah so wait do you
want me to talk about Thailand first or
yeah I got excited ok Thailand I was
actually so supposed to be there right
now well I was planning on being there
but just after like going to school and
stuff last year I couldn't afford it so
this is my vacation week so I'm getting
paid to do this actually I love just
getting paid you're on your podcast tour
now yeah but yeah I went last year and
it was just life-changing like I don't I
don't really know how to describe it
when I tell people about it they're like
oh yeah I'm planning a trip I'm like
it's just so magical like I know it
sounds really Disney but it really is
like everyone's so nice it's so cheap
you're so free there there's so many
different things to do
we just Island hopped but it was really
cool we went to Fifi and that where's
where there's like backlight parties and
everyone just like partying on the beach
all night and just covered in glow paint
just doing different games there's fire
dancers you just meet everyone from
around the globe how do you stumble upon
that though like
you know you meet people in passing but
do you is this just something that
anybody can go to or yeah you fly in but
then you have to take ferries to the
islands okay so we there's all these
islands kind of lined up they'd be like
two hours on boat away from each other
so we planned it out we'll stay on this
island for a couple days see how we like
it and then we'll go to this island :
tow is my favorite it's not touristy at
all and I think that's kind of why I
liked it a lot and I think everyone
should go there before it gets to
receive I'm like bringing two tourists
well does it feel a lot of times I fear
a little bit that the places that aren't
heavy and tourism are like less safe do
you ever feel like unsafe or anything no
I thought I mean I'm sure there's crime
in Thailand I'm not gonna sit here and
be like oh yeah like a hundred percent
so you do whatever you want guys give me
area I seem nice no I felt safe the
whole time I actually would like to do a
solo trip and go back and I felt
completely safe to just do that the
people on the islands were so welcoming
and nice yeah the people you meet we
don't meet any other Americans it was
crazy
we were the only Americans like in all
the groups of people we met they're like
yeah we haven't met anyone from America
it was a lot of Australians a lot of
people from the UK and we met this guy
from Sweden and we kind of made a group
on koh lanta and would hang out every
night there actually there right now oh
you're just like I wish I was there you
know one of them posted and he was out
like our favorite bar where we would
hang out I was like I miss it so much
yeah but they go back so two of the guys
we met they go every year for like a
month
Wow yeah and they go around the same
time so they were like come back next
year we'll be here at the same time and
they are that's like the most epic thing
to do because it's you can live like a
king right it's really cheap when we
went the comparison it was like one u.s.
dollar was 33 bought over there so I
didn't really save up I like took my
check that I had before I went and then
I got paid again when I was there and I
was fine like you know I feel like
people should just like
if you're an American you're like I'm
just it's time for retirement just take
your time and go over there fallout for
six years I've had some friends actually
move over there there's a friend from
Bellingham she teaches English over
there now and just live it yeah
full-time I could see myself doing
something like that like I didn't want
to come home have you have you like you
know nothing that's always ever planned
but have you found yourself like your
perspective changing or like maybe like
I do want to like live somewhere else
have you found yourself like have it
going to places and kind of changing
maybe where you want to end up or yeah
it's crazy I don't know where I want to
end up um that's constantly I don't know
if I've ever really known I do like
Washington like being in New York it was
such a cool experience but it's so
chaotic all the time you could never
find a ton of sense of peace like there
are areas of course you can go to but
like not having a car and everything
being so expensive so being there and
like I'm so happy I got to experience
this but it's time to go back to like
Washington and then I'm in Washington
and I don't really know what my next
move would be but I definitely gone
places when I go to Iceland it feels
like home like if I could afford to live
there
I would I would love to live there but
it's so expensive yeah I don't think
that like people like us cuz we both
grew up in the area like what such you
know such a wooded area it's such a
different compared to New York it's just
so different like I was just in New York
within the last year and it was my it
was my first time there and I did enjoy
it and it was very cool to like ah man
culture and and people are so cool this
is great what we've built
but it's this like there definitely was
this claustrophobia feeling this like
you just I felt a little condensed like
I felt like if I had a couple days there
I think that I would probably be fairly
depressed to myself honestly but yeah I
don't know I think that might just the
there's just a lot intact in one area
but a Iceland Greenland Iceland yeah
because there's always there's one it's
like Greenland has ice right yes but
Iceland doesn't have it has eyes it has
glaciers and stuff but it's mostly it's
like lush green it has
everything man okay tell me about it um
it's just like it's a sense of home so
you go there and I feel like you can
find anything there's mountains there's
volcanoes there's black sand beaches
there's blue lagoons that you can go to
hot spring rivers like we did this hike
and you just find this river and you go
in and it's like a hot tub like it's
just they have everything a far hike was
it accessible um it was a I think I was
like three miles it wasn't hard a ton of
people are doing it but they just bring
wine or like there's a ton of people
just in the river hanging out the
mistake we made
we took a wrap the red-eye and got in in
the morning and we hadn't really ate
anything and we dropped her stuff off at
the air B&B right yeah first day like on
vacation no ham I don't know if we even
brought a lot of water like we were just
like so excited to be there like let's
do this hike and then we kind of bundled
up because it's Iceland you never really
know how the weather is gonna be but the
weather was okay so we're just sweating
like I'm like taking off layers and then
I'm like we haven't ate like I'm just
thinking to myself like we're gonna be
on the news we're gonna die right like
first day of vacation
sorry hit the mic no it was great but
yeah there's just so much there
there's glaciers there's a lot of
different tours you can do scuba diving
one of my favorite places that we saw it
was like two continents it's the only
place where you can swim the two
continents and you can like touch both
of them you do it because it's like five
hundred dollars I'm not scuba certified
and so you have to be and so one of the
next times I go back I definitely want
to prepare for that I feel like I heard
that it's slowly separating though to
where it soon you're not gonna be able
to yeah like I saw pictures on in Syria
not for me exactly um but yeah
underneath and it's looking like it is
but it's still so cool we were kind of
just sitting there watching all the
other divers do it like oh man I wish
thought was a $500 have you ever done
anything like like scuba diving or
anything like because I imagine that as
you're traveling around there's all
these new opportunities that you're like
wow
I really think about getting certified
but it would be beneficial now if things
like that I would love to get certified
there's actually you can do it in
Seattle yeah and so I'm school I know
right
I've thought about it also of my ears
though I don't know because my ears are
pretty touchy with flying oh yeah yeah I
mean no especially yeah so I've
definitely thought about it but one of
the next times I go back to Iceland I I
think I'll do it and just see because
you don't go down very deep like that's
something that I would want I would
really want to do yeah I I I want to do
it and it fascinates me but I have so
weird about water I had when we were in
when we were in Jamaica we were mark and
I we just did snorkeling just like you
know you go out and the people take you
out and it's safe and I think you even
probably have a life vest on if you want
one and you can like duck down for a few
minutes ago swim around me to come back
up and yeah I think I was just
snorkeling yes it was cold right like
the little plastic one yeah yeah yeah
but but like the water was kind of
thrashing and I was so pumped to do it
and I wasn't scared at all but then the
water was just thrusting so much by the
time I got out there and like tried to
get my breath I just kept getting hit
with waves and then I had this like
panic that I couldn't seem to shake but
I still have this like fascination
that's all right so I want to try it
again yeah that definitely that's not
scuba diving by but baby steps I suppose
ya know and especially with being in an
unfamiliar place I can get how you can
get anxiety in places like that
definitely my family and I went to
Hawaii and my stepmom wanted to go swim
with the turtles and it kind of the
ocean kind of got like that and she got
spooked and so she didn't do it and so I
think it was just not knowing what can
happen like yeah well and there's just
like once you get spooked
I don't know water just weird cause once
you get spooked it's like okay the only
way that I can feel fully safe from this
and if I get completely out of it like
that's the way yeah because me I
remember I was just floating on my back
at one point just like dude chill out
just stop stop freaking out you find you
know just floating along yeah but so
backing up we mentioned your ears do you
want to talk about that I think that's
this interest
I'm talking about so you have like
Bionic ears now and they drain fluid
down your throat that's what I know
yes so when I had no ear issues before I
started flying and then I never thought
about it like that's one thing starting
the job you don't really think about
health and like all those things you're
like so excited about it
about a year after I started flying I
started noticing my ears weren't popping
anymore and they just didn't feel normal
like I don't know what it's like for
ears my ears to feel normal I feel like
there's something I was off about him
right and then the feeling would kind of
go away but then would come back like a
couple months later and I'm like oh
maybe this is something I could live
with maybe it's just I'm working too
much and then at that point they'll
start to not pop or something
but then it just continued to get worse
throughout the years and this has
happened with some flight attendants
that I've talked to you like I ended up
getting the tube surgery last year
because they drill a hole in your
eardrum so essentially there's air flow
and you don't really have to worry about
popping and pressure because it really
keeps it open yeah it's open so you
don't have to worry about it building up
and then releasing and so that has
helped me in a sense with the popping
but then when I got this procedure done
I think there's fluid trapped behind my
eardrum and there's just been constant
draining in my ears and it's not like
draining out of your ears I know it's
not like what you go in the shower you
know and you have hot water and it comes
out it's this feeling sensation I don't
know it's like dripping I can feel drops
and it's gonna mean it's all connected
yeah yeah it's going down to my throat
and at first it happened every once in a
while but definite it happened before
the procedure too but it's everyday now
after the procedure and so it just seems
like things aren't getting better with
that and so I got I went in this last
week and they think maybe it's allergies
now I don't know we're trying to like
test a bunch of different theories with
that so I bet I know like I'm not the
only one I don't think there's like a
ton of flight attendants that have
severe ear issues like this but I've
talked to some because they were like
get the tube surgery but they the tubes
pop out after a year so that's also
something that I would have to do every
couple years to get one and you go to so
many shows like we've been we've been
friends for a long time we've been going
to show since we were both young
I took Jake to his first show you took
you took me to rescue I do let's tell
that story actually what we'll Lubeck
this is why your ear started you took me
to my first show Rosco and it was right
after high school we were both going to
the LCC Community College in town and
then I think I think it was just like
you just asked me like do you want to go
what was that you asked me because I
said something that was very much like
noob I don't I just remember it was a
school night because we had a class
together and I think I turned to you and
I was like dude do you want to go to the
show and I think he thought it was a
band or something member oh yeah no no
no I did think I was a bit I did think
it was a band so I remember when I like
met all your friends like cuz I hadn't
met them home yet and so we go to this
house and it's someone new house I'm
trying to like okay like look these are
new people yeah like I want to be cool
you know and then one of them goes like
so do you do you listen to a lot of
dubstep and I go yeah I think I've heard
of him I think was Glenn I remember
clanking I like Jimmy like oh this guy
dude but back then I don't even know
like but but it totally changed my life
that was like the craziest that was such
a fun night like I remember I think I
just absolutely got hammered and didn't
ya lail my arms are hunting a circle I'm
sure but yeah at the Roseland is that
the Roseland yeah it was a great 10 or
11 2011 and then is that like when we
that was first when I got introduced to
electronic music was around that time I
really it for you yeah yeah what cuz
then I then I came home well cuz we
would listen to like gosh nah not
Bassnectar remember
I'm out like base hunter and like
they're like even older like there's
like techno techno Beauty yeah like a
but we would listen to like stuff like
that but never like get into it but
going to something like that live and
like seeing a dude like wait like
someone is he's even paid to like make
those sounds that they're wow the [__]
is he doing that like what is happening
and everyone's just having a great time
cheering him on oh and people are
bumping into you and saying sorry like
everyone was so nice like I was probably
a total just drunk jerk and people are
just like hey man it's great to meet you
drunk jerk they start dancing with you
yeah you know like dancer goes we always
need dancer girls yeah it's such a sick
environment I'm very grateful that you
turned me on to the electricity but your
years definitely took I feel like you
know you said you didn't get it tested
before like like doing the flight
attendant thing but I'm sure it had some
effect just going to so many things and
always having headphones on or whatever
we always do yeah because even in high
school as going to concerts and
festivals I've always just really been
into music and one of the first things I
said to the doctor when I had to do
hearing test I was like this I was
thinking in my head this all can't be
from flying well the pressure aspect of
it definitely but with the hearing loss
I'm just thinking about all the shows
I've been to and all the times we've
been right there so close to the
speakers in the stage and not only that
me being a music lover
I mean musics in my everyday life
whether it's blasting in my car in my
room and my headphones you know and so I
know I've known that's obviously not
good for me and so I think it all tied
together very not sense
well I dude I think that's just the art
of getting older right is just like
everything you love you can't have all
at once
you gotta just slowly start balancing
these things and it's like you can't go
listen to as many hours of music and as
loud as he always used to and yeah
definitely especially with dubstep and
all this stuff we all the shows we used
to go to I mean it's just always it's
hard on your ears and we would always
get to the front you know I just yeah at
the Roseland I remember just being at
the front for a
shows and is it crizzley Oh crazy we've
seen crazy important a few times yeah we
were in the very front but next to the
speakers we used to do that oh I
remember that show we talked about the
Bohemia warehouses yeah yeah we we
talked we used to go to a lot of shows
there was one that Mackenzie remember
the other night that I had gotten thrown
out of I think that was a bit of a
warehouse yeah I was I was caught buying
a Molly Rancher is the verdict yeah you
know what's what's so funny I mean I
don't know I was so young back then but
what's so funny is I was we were thrown
out but then the girl who sold it sold
the Molly Rancher to me was also thrown
out and like we talked afterwards and
then I still bought a Molly we had two
from her and it was like shitty like it
like I don't I don't know I remember
like being super unhappy about this
Molly Rancher and then all these shows
I mean tied into remember we you start
throwing outdoor parties those are so
much fun yeah yeah we've mentioned in a
couple times it's cool because there's a
couple people that have been on here and
you start talking like where do we meet
or how do we know each other and a lot
of people's like have came into my life
hearing about those parties are starting
from there or whatever yeah dude we
started throwing like got interest in
electronic music but like where we live
in between Portland and Seattle here
yeah it's it's like a it's a mega small
town for sure like we have like you know
our County is is fairly large but it
still is small town so like electronic
music is still like like the only reason
it's kind of D okay now is because it's
like normalized in pop music you know
yeah but back then it was like you you
didn't you couldn't hear it anywhere
like so we started making like it I was
so obsessed with it and our friend group
was so obsessed that we started throwing
outdoor parties and stuff yeah there's
so much fun yeah just uh it was cool
I've told that I've told about here but
essentially what it was listener if you
haven't heard of this before
they were renegade parties and what I
would do is I would get a bunch of
equipment a bunch of Lights generator
speakers a bunch of homies who are super
super good DJs who are just down to
throw down and give everybody an hour
slot I would essentially give people the
date and the theme so they knew like
what
to get and then they knew like what like
it general area like what count I think
I would just say like it's always in
this county or whatever yeah but and
they knew the the date and then so I day
of or the day before I would release the
address or the directions and you'd have
for like a be in on the circle you'd
have to like know the right people to
get the text or yeah I remember there
would be like a line of cars like ten
cars following each other oh man those
are such good times I mean yeah
everything after 21 like those are when
we couldn't get into bars or like all
right like this is what we're gonna do
well that's what dude I was like I love
this [__] like this is so good my whole
thing is cool cuz as I get older I kind
of preaching about it I'm like always
like I'm always telling people I do do
it yourself like put yourself on and
it's kind of funny like I didn't even
when I first started I just wanted to
play electronic music I just wanted to
be a cool DJ I just wanted to hear
electronic music and so I just made my
own [__] I just made my own party and I
headlined in myself I made my own I made
myself cool yeah yeah I am the headliner
but it was cool though like you could I
mean you could hype yourself up and like
you know those things were so fun they
were a total blast we definitely been to
so many cool concerts yeah we went to a
concert this week yeah we just went to
derma Dermott kennedy one thing I was
going to I was actually almost about to
rant on Instagram just because the
nature of who I am but we can talk about
this people yelling
during the performance like so Dermot
kennedy he's like he sings this just
beautifully like you're bawling your
eyes out such a beautiful song I cried
yeah and then he's like he goes on a
next song and he's just like so this
song was about this very difficult time
with my demons and and he's just like
being heart felon explaining this like
intricate emotional song and [__] are
in the crowd it's cold yeah I turned
around cuz we're in the stands and
there's ice war this girl's gonna fall
like she was so drunk and just like
flailing everywhere but I mean which it
wasn't that type of concert it was very
intimate and just very personal like you
and Shaylee talked about before we
something he is shy I feel like he's
very shy and it probably takes it not
takes them a lot of guts but to just be
so raw and vulnerable and like this is
what happened to me and this is why I
wrote this song and I'm so happy it's
helping you and then you got this girl
in the background like yelling whatever
comes to mind
yeah while you sing it and I'm like just
let him talk like people I think that
I've noticed that over all the different
genres cuz there's there's a moment in
every genre like even EDM there's
breakdowns that are just like people in
the crowd are crying like you were just
banging your head against the [__]
wall two minutes ago but now you're
singing cinema holding your best
friend's hand crying your eyes out
there's parts you know it's it's not the
equivalent of him like explaining that I
made this art in this piece oh yeah
there's moments where in the crowd your
job is to shut your damn mouth second
how you do it but I think that people
are so afraid of silence they like panic
when they have silence when they're like
oh my god nobody's saying anything I
need to yell I need to go whoa we're
gonna go yeah we're gonna go I love you
derma or I love you whoever's on stage
it's just this absurd thing that me so
me I like I'm just a DJ so it's a way
easier for me like it's not like it's
like I'm pouring my heart and soul out
or anything but people yelling [__]
throws me off well yeah because you got
so many things to do up there yeah and
you're trying to pay attention and when
people are especially if they're saying
like really off-the-wall things it's
like what and then you stop and you lose
your train of thought while you're in
the middle of something yeah and then I
get overly emotional and and then you
break down then I break down and then I
turn off the music and then I just turn
on the mic and then I turn on more music
but it's just violin music and it's just
I'd actually love that
and then the lights go down and I put an
auto-tune on my voice I say I want to
talk about my problems for a while in
the clubs like what the [__] is
happening I do this whole time I love it
I love it I would so be like alright
let's lay it all on the table what's on
your mind I know I always like when
there when the artist gets in the
microphone okay how's everybody doing
tonight
there was this this meme that I saw and
now is think of it like well you know
I'm glad you asked I've been kind of
going through some things lately
honestly thank goodness you asked I've
been really wanting to get this off my
chest
um but yeah okay so yeah Jake and I have
been to a lot of festivals a lot of
shows I kind of want to talk about what
the fest
I definitely want to talk because I
didn't even know about it until you guys
went and they invited me and then it was
probably the best festival I've ever
been to okay lay this out for someone
for someone who was like probably been
to a concert they never knew any
festival like any massive let alone an
immersive festival like describe it for
these people I like yeah right here
comes like the Disney lingo it's magical
I felt so free um it's it's one of those
places I turned my phone off for like
the first three days was it I turned we
ought through the night before and I was
so sick yeah we took an RV there and so
because once you're on the fact like
once you're there you're there it's like
you you enter the gate you show your
tickets you're in like that you know
they check your RV and make sure you
don't have like an ak-47 or whatever but
once you're in you're in but anyway so
we took the RV there and it's this very
comfortable thing and we figured we'd
have like the people who weren't driving
one figure we have a couple drinks on
the way
mistake and Mackenzie has never used me
oh the concentrate that comes in the
small thing like the size of the smaller
than the palm of your hand you squirt in
a couple squirts and water and here
alcohol and it's fantastic what
Mackenzie thought that you needed to use
the whole bottle well I was like what is
this and they're like just put a meal in
it so I'm like all right like we didn't
explain that it was a concentrate yeah
so I like squeeze so I had water and
vodka and I squeezed this whole meal
container in there and I'm I'm drinking
it and I'm looking at no so tart
yeah I'm looking at our whole group of
friends like at their cups and I'm like
how how the hell are they enjoying the
street like fruit punch and I'm like
this is disgusting how much of it do you
drink though because the whole night no
I didn't drink the whole thing I think I
drank half because I remember turning to
Kelly and I was like you guys drink this
[__] and everyone's like yeah looking at
me so weird and I'm like try mine and I
just remember he took a sip and like
spit it out right away
and he's like what is this I'm like you
told me to put a meal in it and they're
like not the whole container well it was
all this sugar and we were on this bumpy
road in the RV and I was sick I was so
everyone's partying all my friends are
drunk dancing singing as long as I'm
green sweating feeling like I'm gonna
beat my guts out I think we're like
going up high elevation to the guy who
took the back way and so we're just
going up a mountain you're in is in the
very back the IV so it's super bouncy
and it was just on like gravel so it's
going up and down and I'm in the back
and I'm like and oh I remember I just
wanted to be left alone and the bathroom
wasn't working and everyone was drunk
and they were peeing in this bucket
remember there was like a bucket back
there so everyone's like hey Mack like
I'm just like trying to rest and it runs
like I got a PT real quick and I'm like
oh you have plotted this out somehow it
has become your destiny could be in this
situation but no it was once I got there
so the the journey there yeah that was
not
but once we got there it was just it was
so incredible so free um okay back to
what I was saying I turned my phone off
the first two two or three days and then
the last day I was like I want to get a
couple pictures because they have
artwork this forest
and it's just so so awesome like you you
start walking down this path and there
it will be just woods and then there
will be a couch with like a hookah bar
like there's hookah set up until people
just sit on this couch and start Gabbar
in the woods yeah yeah and then you keep
you go back on the path and then it's
just woods and then you'll hit like
these clam shells like these beds where
people are like laying down and then you
keep going and then yeah it's just
completely dark woods and then there's
Mario Cart like people are literally
playing like Mario Cart and so you're
just discovering all this different type
of art and like there's a paint station
and then you'll come across like the
first stage and so there will be like an
artist playing and then you can go down
a different path and you just hit all
these different things that people have
set up and it's really cool the people
where I didn't meet one person I didn't
like oh my gosh it was oh yeah the
people the energy there because of the
people it's like it's this understanding
you have between each other like you
feel very safe there yeah and there's
yoga oh yes yeah yeah and yeah I turned
my phone off oh yeah and one of the
stages is um three pools and so you're
just dancing
was it claude one stroke on one stroke
yeah he's really good flamingo hat yeah
that was one of the artists and it was
just so much fun it was incredible and
it was a plate like I didn't need my
phone I didn't want my phone I didn't
think about like texting anybody like
any social media I just wanted to be
there and I wanted to be present with my
group of friends and it was just perfect
I feel like if I the in situations like
that like a rathas festival it feels
like my phone would almost like make me
but come back to reality i back oh my
gosh yeah like I forgot like I'm living
in heaven right now yeah I got about
that you know until you're on your phone
yeah let's talk about social media I
know I'm all anti more anti social media
I'm back and forth about it yeah yeah I
feel probably like a year and a half ago
I just started realizing I I feel I
asked myself the question a lot is this
making me happy with a lot of different
aspects of my life yeah you know if I'm
feeling some sort of way about something
if you really have to ask yourself is it
making me happy
it probably fully isn't if you get to
that place and so there's different
things I went through through my life
but yeah social media I'll be like I'll
get off of it and I'll just be like why
do I feel the need to spend a couple
hours on my phone every day checking up
on everyone else's lives like why and I
do like I love keeping up with my
friends it's not that I don't hate
social media but it's like why is our
phone this prized possession that we
feel like it's like a prize if you don't
have your phone all day you're like I
need to get to my phone I need to look
at it see who's wrote me and stuff
and so I started out by deleting Twitter
cuz I was just like I felt like I'd get
drunk and post my feelings that's what
don't abuse it yeah so I would like I
remember I woke up one morning and I was
like oh [__] like I posted something
away yeah it wasn't bad but it was just
like on there long enough where it's
like well everyone saw it and it was it
wasn't bad and it was just why do they
need to know how I'm feeling like they
don't need to know that was just like an
extension of what I was feeling at that
moment I don't overall think bad yeah
and so I feel like it's an outlet for a
lot of people which is great because
Twitter's funny like sometimes I do miss
it yeah and but that I asked myself what
is something you can live without like
what's the first app to go and instantly
I was like I need to get rid of my
Twitter I think that's what Shaylee did
to his Twitter was the first to go she's
like I can't live without that yeah I
was like and now I don't even think
about it honestly like the only time
people will be like oh someone posted
that on Twitter I'm like
yeah Twitter is the thing you know but I
feel like I love Instagram but the thing
that I'll do you sometimes I delete my
snaps like my app for like a week nice
and then I'll be like all right like if
I feel like it like I'll get back on and
so I do that sometimes it's not a week
sometimes it's a couple days but
sometimes a feeling will come over me
and I'm like do I really need to be yeah
on my phone this much um you know how it
tells you how long you had screen time
right I remember at one point it was
like an average of like 6 hours a day
and I don't know it's so crazy I don't
know if it was like Netflix involved you
know like I don't know entirely like I
didn't look at it and see but that was
one of the things I'm like whoa like I'm
just there's this whole world going on
around me and I'm staring at the screen
for six hours a day and like I was like
that needs to get brought down I
remember like a couple weeks ago that
said two hours and so I was like which
isn't good you know yeah I'm six hours
that's profound yeah I'm like I feel
like a lot of the time on the plane too
there's you know on long flights it's
like there's nothing to do you get done
with your service and one thing I've
been trying to teach myself I love
reading
and so I've told myself if I feel like I
need to get on social media pick up a
book
I like that I'll just start reading and
so on the plane I've tried I'm like
trying to train myself to do that
right and so yeah I'll just start
reading a book and instead of doing that
yeah I think that's a really good idea
Shaylee has been doing that more lately
- because she at the beginning of the
month a month till he did the rest of
her social media like she just wanted to
take a 30 day break and she's been
reading more as well I think that we we
a lot of the things that we do we don't
really like know why we do it we we have
like like art so our a it's for example
like we're the same age we grew up
graduating the same year so we grew up
you were at a different middle school
than me but I think that we had started
to get more technology more cell phones
when we were still in middle school so
the iPhone came out and O's
I think our weight I don't remember
honestly yeah but it's but it's just
interesting so essentially what I'm
saying is is we like our age we rode the
technology wave like we it was like we
got all the cool [__]
we were like the test we're the guinea
pigs like our age group or 2728 now you
gotta do MySpace yeah we were the first
ones like MSN Messenger we like we were
we got it experience all these cool
things like we're at the beginning like
when they were first popping up and they
just they carried their momentum and we
just continued to use them and they
spread out to Facebook Twitter Instagram
whatever and they're so cool like
they're so cool but there was never
really up until like two years ago there
was never a moment in my life where I
had where I stopped and said like wait
why am I using this like nothing it was
like oh like you you've just been sucked
into this thing that sucks and it's
terrible vortex it's just like no I
think that anything in your life you
should be able to take a glance at it
stop take glance at it and say like mmm
do I want to do this do is this is
beneficial is this what I want to do and
I feel like yeah it's we had so many
cool things our age but a lot of us I'm
noticing more and more on this podcast
I'm talking to more people they kind of
did the same thing like I just sort of
noticed that it wasn't what I wanted to
do as pulling me in a little too often
and then we find ways to you know you
don't have to delete it if that's not
what works for you but if there's ways
like you said I really like that just if
you have the little intuition of like a
let's delete it for a couple days a week
yeah do with it I like that I think
that's good I think it's because I'm
like I like and it's weird because when
I do do that I'm learning so much more
about myself throughout that week you
know rather than oh I'm bored I'm just
gonna get on my phone which of course I
still have social media I still get on
I still have posted things you know and
I'm not saying I'm going to delete all
of it I've just really been asking
myself questions because honestly like
I'm conflicted because social media it
can be a beautiful thing like I follow
so many artists and I learn about travel
on Instagram and I follow a lot of
musicians and I find out about tours and
new albums coming out
and I do like seeing my friends posts
you know so it is it can be such a
beautiful thing I think it does cause a
lot of issues and relationships are just
everyday life too though and so that's
why I'm trying to find that balance with
that yeah no that's good we have to find
balance we have to like set our own
rules for balance too because it's not
like these companies are like trying to
I mean there's little things where you
can set your screen time and stuff you
know there is little things like that
all over but they still take our
initiative you know like the companies
can offer things uh trying to help us
out and not have us just sucked into the
phone all day if yeah if they want to
that is but we still have to do the work
and be like you know what I happen on my
phone or you know what I'm gonna try to
take 30 days off for 10 days off or week
off whatever well honestly it it is
refreshing I think yeah like you were
saying people started asking themselves
I feel like in the last couple years to
this last year especially I started
asking myself a lot more questions like
yeah why am I doing this you know you
never thought I never thought about it
before it was just crazy like now that
you point that out and then yeah I don't
yeah I just been asking myself a lot
about what I want and things like that
it's a cool age to be I'm enjoying these
conversations on the podcast cuz you
know so far I've had like similar age
people like you know over between like
24 and 30 around that age and there's a
lot of it that is definitely just
maturing you know just becoming an adult
for sure like that's definitely a lot of
it like just growing up in a lot of
senses a lot of these changes but we're
also at an immensely peculiar incredible
and confusing crossroads with technology
and like just just growing up with
technology so close to us and so we we
know so much information you and I know
so much because we've always had a phone
that you know whatever it since seventh
grade since eighth grade we've had a
phone that think about all the amount of
times that we have used that to like
look up an answer and get that really
quick those are however many answers
those are that many more answers we have
then the generation before us
didn't have the phones or whatever yeah
there's just so much to go into it so
it's good that we're taking a look yeah
you can access anything it's kind of
scary like when you think about for you
it's yeah I'm like you could literally
find anything most anything you want on
the internet if you try hard enough
right you know that tech lab the dark
web what's your favorite dirt my rap
lyrics nobody say I heard this thing
Duncan Trussell talked about at one time
I don't even know if he intended it to
be this like super mysterious sentence
as he was describing it but he was like
so think about technology right you have
you know whatever jumped from TVs to
like where we have starting having
computers and then become personal
computers they're like in people's homes
rich people kind of have computers and
they're on the desk they're on the table
right yeah and then over the years more
and more people like then in the port
you know not just poor people but like
everybody every if you have a modern
household you have a computer it's on
the desk and then time goes on and the
computers get smaller and they get
lighter and then their laptops you can
pick it up off the desk and you can move
it around you could take it at the
coffee shop with you and then you have
cell phones it's not connected to the
wall anymore it slowly took it moved
itself from the wall to be more
important and now you can leave it you
can leave the house with it now and now
you can leave the town with it and now
it's in your pocket at all times and
slowly it's moving from next to our leg
here up our bodies it's gonna be on our
glasses our Google glasses our neuro
chips whatever it is it's it's
interesting he basically laid it out to
be this he's like it's like this
creature who created itself on the table
and it slowly has moved more
incorporating with us like it's it's
part of us you do not leave in today's
modern world you don't leave the house
without your phone it is a part of us
now there's a lot of us like it's not
that you would die and explode into a
million pieces
without it but go if everybody lost
their phone for two weeks all of a
sudden all the phone all the phones in
the world just fry we would lose our
[__] minds
yeah we wouldn't know what to do it's
that's scary but no that's so
interesting you said that because I've
never thought about that and then it
goes to the Apple watch like not only is
it a watch now you can call you can text
so it's like oh and you can't have your
phone in your hand don't worry you have
this made
attached you can see what everyone's
writing in we couldn't eat your holiday
well so I study you've all know Harare
have you ever heard of him he's a an
author and historian you've all know her
he's awesome like I have was a book
secretary but essentially I was watching
this thing he talks about how where data
is now like such a commodity like
there's so much data on people they have
so much information on people that it's
now time where a lot of our actions
aren't necessarily our own you know if
you're if you're looking at your phone
so often like if you're like like I so I
took my I took a year break off social
media I was someone who was on social
media hardcore like I love social media
I worked at it at a lumber mill and I
was able to pretty much be on social
media whenever I wanted with my left
hand as long as I'm work with my right
hand like it was if your deeds not your
job Jesus Christ just there's a machine
that will just Eve you and not Carol's
keep going but anyway we essentially the
fact that we have data points on
everything now everything is such a
commodity so you can your actions aren't
necessarily always your actions when
you're always looking at your phone like
so being off social media things that
would this word sucks but trigger me if
I would see certain words they would
make me want to like post about it or
think about it or text my friend about
it or whatever but when you don't have
those words or those things coming into
you you don't have a response tourism so
let's say Donald Trump for example the
word Trump like if you like nowadays in
this 2020 2019 if you see the word Trump
you have a feeling attached to it you
have something like whether you hate him
whether you don't want to you like him
it it activates something in you right
like something it turns on you have an
opinion no totally when you wake up in
the morning and the news says Donald
Trump whatever then you're thinking of
that every day so it's it's just
interesting it's just very important I
think for all of us to kind of look at
like like who are we without the phone
and if our actions are different like
what's that all about is someone else
kind of pushing us towards things that
we maybe shouldn't be doing
we don't want to do like that that
aren't our intuitive
yeah actions it's just so cool so I've
known Jake for so long it's so cool to
see your journey like yeah we've been
good friends until just like the amount
of growth the last couple years like
even I know it probably started with you
asking yourself questions as I feel like
the state I'm in like right about now it
probably started with that because I
know I don't know if you want to talk
about it like just the struggle but you
just like overcame everything you've
been through and you're on top and it's
just so awesome to see yeah well I'm
glad yeah I thank you thank you for
pointing it out that that's how it is it
definitely wasn't it started questioning
what I was doing my I was just so
depressed and so I mean I wanted to die
I wanted to take my own life and so I
would think about all the time and I I
had a night where I was just like I mean
of course it's more than one night but
it seems like this night sticks out and
it was just like it was like an
ultimatum almost it was like dude if
you're gonna do it do it or like get to
work and see if you can figure out what
the hell's going on here because a lot
of times we we in in me especially like
things happen to us or or thoughts come
at us or like we think of things and we
just think that that's who we are we
just think that every thought that pops
in our head is who we are like okay well
other people can walk past a knife
without thinking like weird thoughts
about it like what why can't I I must
just be an evil piece of [__] you know
so you you have these thoughts that you
assume and if you don't stop and
question them if you don't say like wait
why am i doing these things or is that
me is that what that means you know and
then if you don't have the answers right
away you you start looking up books you
start searching it you start looking on
YouTube you start listening the podcast
you start finding other people who have
had similar things and you learn that
you're not alone and you learn that
you're the problems that you're that
you're going through have have any end
holes that you can crawl out of you know
yeah so I don't know yeah it's it's it's
interesting to see where it's led like
it seems like I don't I always like you
know I have my dreams and I have my like
that would be cool to do but it seems
like things just keep popping up like
the podcast seems like it kind of
created itself in a way you know it just
seemed like it's like oh of course I'm
gonna do a podcast it's just the next
step right here you know yeah and you
never know where it will lead thank you
for sharing that by the way cuz I know
like it's hard to be open about stuff
like that sometimes but I think over the
last couple years as a society it's been
really great that we are more open and
vulnerable about these things because
before I felt like it wasn't talked
about enough no one talked about
depression no one talked about suicide
that much and stuff and then the more
people have opened up about it it is
normal not normal that you know you're
not gonna feel open yeah you're not
gonna feel a hundred percent all the
time and I think a majority of people do
have those thoughts but then when it's
not talked about you're like yeah like
how you felt you're like I'm the only
one that feels this way like yeah I'm
stuck and it's like you aren't stuck I
mean I've been a couple years ago I was
at a point and not a point in my life
where I was kind of similar and it was
just like you just anyone listening you
have to push through it's so crazy like
it sounds so cliche but it's you really
do come out on top and I know something
else will happen again in my life work I
get brought down like but that's about
maturing like you I know that's gonna
happen I know I'm gonna like be so upset
probably this year next year something
traumatic is gonna happen again in your
life but you look back at these times
you're like if I made it through that
like I'd uh I know I'm gonna hurt for a
couple months I'm gonna cry but I am
gonna make it through this as well so
it's just cool I don't know it's it's a
journey man what doesn't kill you makes
you stronger that's Kelly Clarkson came
on the other day and I was like I want
to yell this song so loud it's so tight
that's a great song honestly you should
probably see I can honestly say I think
that's the only way Eric I know from
that song we can put a pig in it I can
look up the lyrics
I can grab the guitar we can just wing
it right now while that while the guests
are listening yeah this is really a
podcast mean we're just gonna start a
band honestly he's a band guys welcome
to the band gotcha listeners I can't see
I can rap in the background
have you have you thought of your raps
yeah have they been floating around yet
no so I wrote this rap in high school
and it was at mckinsey houses house she
threw really good parties um and so I I
wrote it with Scott graves and Ian
Fulton and I just remember we was three
sat down and we're like Mac we're gonna
we're gonna write you a rap and we just
like went back and forth and it's about
me and then I remember I stood up on the
kitchen island this party over and I
wrapped it like I read it off this paper
I wrapped it and I remember like
everyone was cheering me on I'm like
haha whatever you know I thought people
would like forget about it the next day
and it kind of just people just think
you know no it was not good like let's
just make that very clear but I remember
like I let the listeners decide we could
we go what no I kept the paper and I
remember I like brought it to school
it's me and I ended up memorizing it and
so if I would get drunk at a party and
someone would bring it up
I would I would wrap it I still know the
route but no I know I think I'd be
willing to bet now I mean I guess I get
a little bit when we work with interns
when I'm like flying around there is
more access like young kids in high
school have more access like making
beats and like putting on a tune on
their voice and like rapping and stuff
like that which super excites me I'm
wondering like none of us really had
that back then like just rapping for fun
yeah I would love to see that happen
that's something I talk about in this
podcast la is like kind of that mindset
of like dude you don't have to make
music to be famous you don't have to
make music to show it to anybody you
don't have to play guitar to show it to
anybody you can do these things because
it's enjoyable for the human experience
to rap over a beat with your friends
yeah you know place it's like mess up on
guitar or fail and play some terribly
wrong keys on piano while you're
learning like it's really cool that
nowadays I'm seeing I guess a little bit
more and more kids being able to try it
although I do think they're trying to
get famous which sucks but which sucks
no music is such a beautiful thing I
mean it's such everybody it's one of the
number-one parts of my life like I don't
know where I would be without music
someone like Dermott like just so raw
being able like this guy is able to
write a song and you can just feel the
emotion like you can his lyrics it can
relate his songs can relate to anyone
like you listen to him I mean I I
started crying at the concert during my
favorite song and I remember the first
time I ever listened to it in my car I
just broke down and started crying which
song was it what it's called without
fear yeah I don't got Shaylee - yeah
it's the it's a name of the album
and it's the last song I remember
listening the whole album and I didn't
cry I'm like oh my gosh this is so great
and then this last song he like closes
out and he's so raw and you can relate
to it and you start thinking back on
times in your life what you've gone
through and like I just the lyrics just
hit me so hard I just started bawling in
my car I knew when he played it on
Tuesday I was gonna cry I think I was
thinking about of course I was but I was
thinking about like what's different for
like people like you and I we've always
gone to so many concerts like what is
different between you and I and the
[__] who just think they should
be yell like a maybe they're just drunk
sure but so there's something that like
you can kind of look around a room in
people who are let's say you have a room
full of people who are self-conscious
for example or people who aren't fully
there for the artists they're gonna be
kind of engaged with their phone they're
gonna be kind of like looking up at the
stage but also like if there's someone
that moves they're gonna make a look
over at them they're gonna be listening
to the sounds are and they're not super
engaged but there's this thing that I
don't know that everybody knows you can
do it's this magical gift that you have
as a human I'm not I'm not gonna shut
the [__] up
that's where but but no no no k'naan
says so there's a thing that happens
when you're at somebody you an artist
that you like
an artist you've never seen before like
it you can your visual perception you're
looking at the stage right and you zone
off to this degree of like like to where
there's nothing that can make you move
your head at all besides like bouncing
to the beat but like you almost kind of
like blur what you're seeing like it's a
it's a thing that's like normal for you
or not like we've been doing this
forever so it doesn't seem profound but
I'm actually I think that actually
there's many people who don't give
themselves this I think they don't allow
themselves to just like dude next time
you're at a concert next time you got a
show gaze at the dude on stage and
commit to like not looking anywhere for
20 minutes just or 15 minutes whatever
it is and just be just a lot of unlock
your jaw and drool if you need to like
just stare at the lights and be in what
this artist is saying completely remove
yourself don't add yourself don't think
that you need to yell like clap if you
want to clap cool but yeah remove
yourself I don't know I don't know maybe
I'm overanalyzing is no I feel like I I
can relate like I do that I love music
so much and know when I like an artist
seeing them live is just such a
beautiful thing because you know how for
someone to get up in front of an
audience that big I mean like I've seen
people at the motifs that you know like
these are huge stadiums there for them
to get up there and just be so raw like
not only they recorded this album alone
you know like they could be raw alone
but then they'd have to bring it to the
stage and stuff and I just feel like
people need to respect that and people
don't understand that I've met a lot of
people though so a lot of our friends
like some of my friends don't really
appreciate music which is great like I
think I'm just like so invested in the
music you know but I feel yeah like I
feel like they don't really see like
some people they're like oh I don't
really like listen to the lyrics I'm
like do you get this song are you
hearing what this person is saying like
what they just said yeah and then some
people are like like or if it's not the
beat that they want you know there's so
much beautiful music like the genres
that I love the full range like I love
everything but if it's not like beat if
it's slow they're like no I can't listen
to that
right you know and so but if you really
just take time to listen and just put
yourself in the artists shoes like
you're saying I had the concert just
really focus on that artist I mean you
paid money to see them already why would
why wouldn't you you know but no I
totally agree yeah it's such a beautiful
thing that like everybody has access to
and nowadays the production like like
he's not a huge artist right now but
like he's able to have enough money to
like I mean like his lights were sick
that like the stage effects were sick
his band was sick they had like a lot of
cool like it sounded great you know
nowadays any concert you go to visually
and hearing wise hearing wise that's not
a great sense but it's gonna hear it's
gonna look and sound great no that's
definitely like something awesome that
we have I know it's kind of selfish but
because like I feel like we discover a
lot of artists that maybe people in this
town don't know like Brockhampton for
example a lot like I feel like they're
becoming more famous but at first feel
were like who's Rockhampton like what is
abroad Campton what does that mean but I
don't know where I was I lost you and I
thought oh I was saying I'm sorry I
totally summed up I said maybe it's
selfish but when these people are so
good and then I feel like sometimes when
they become famous it just like I'm I
want all these artists to have so much
big success but then like I just feel I
don't know how to describe it you know
what I'm talking about yeah it's this
bittersweet moment where you watch an
artist grow and you're like you deserve
this and I knew you'd get here but also
I selfishly just wish it was 150 people
in the crowd you touched my hand because
it's such a small crowd and yeah I
remember before Odessa was even like a
thing I was living in Bellingham and I
saw them play for free like they were
know at the college like they literally
were they were going to Western and they
played out on the lawn for free like no
one talking people didn't know who they
were and I remember like watching them
and being like wow like I really like
these guys and then it's been so cool to
watch them go from like the buff to
Barclays Center in New York like they
three nights at the wamu in Seattle and
like you know this they're like yes you
made it but then it's like oh it's hard
to get tickets now all these different
rings when your favorite hardest blows
up dude they're they're like a Odessa is
one that I'm never I'm always shocked
with Odessa at who people Ickes it like
there will be people who like put it on
or listen to it or I'll say Odessa and
they'll say like and I'm a quick wait
you know does it like cool so many
different types of people it's
definitely a language yeah yeah yes all
right how many times you seen Odessa
just once her a just mine yeah I think
the last time when I saw him in
Bellingham was eight if I counted
correctly when was the best time that
you saw them you remember oh my gosh I
don't know every time so special um I
really so I mean it's different I saw
them do a DJ set at the buff last year
which was really cool like it wasn't
there they were just mixing what's the
difference between a regular set and DJ
set for listeners who don't know so
their regular set they have songs on
their album um that they perform and
it's just like strictly their own music
that they're performing with the DJ set
they'll mix anything from like top 42
they just mix a ton of songs together so
you could be hearing cardi B and then
they'll mix in one of their songs with
it to a different beat and then it will
go to a different song it's not full
songs different clips absolutely did I
describe that right yeah pretty much
you know a lot of times they do like a
like if they have three artists in the
band but they are only happy to and
they'll say it's a DJ set because it's
not gonna be the full thing so they'll
cuddle yeah like one artist like the
festival lineups inside like right yeah
I am Nero Nero did that often because
they would I think there's three people
in a row but they would only ever travel
with one or something yeah um yeah so
the buff was cool because every time
I've seen them that was their music
which is great but they just like we're
having so much fun
um clay was hammered so there's two guys
in Odessa doing all the work and the
other guy was just something like he's
like [__] yeah
like let's party and then Harrison just
sitting there like doing all the DJ work
and then it was I just remember looking
at my friend and clay wasn't even facing
the stage like he just had a beer he has
a hole in his beer and he's looking at
the like the projector behind him like
there are yeah he's not even like these
are [__] graphics these are sick
yeah he's literally just like dancing
and facing and I was like dude he's so
[__] up but it was just really cool
like they were just having so much fun
what cuz I was definitely having so much
fun on the stage but it was cool to see
them in LM like an element like that and
we were super close because the buff is
such a small venue in Bellingham so but
the other time I don't know I don't the
time I saw them at the wall knew this
last tour was pretty cool I mean I know
it sounds weird to people that don't
listen to music it was kind of like a
journey like from the very first song
they literally take you like it it
didn't feel like a concert it felt like
an experience no that's that's
absolutely what it is yeah I think
they're so there is we were talking
about like differences and different
countries like there's certain music
people go to party they go to get drunk
we're going to go out we're gonna go
like we're gonna see this DJ we're gonna
go see this guy and he's kind of party
we're gonna dance around that's like a
whole different genre of music that it's
like okay I'm gonna - I'm gonna paint
this story with sound and you're gonna
decipher it with your soul you know I'm
so beautiful but it's hard I feel like
these lines get mixed up a little bit
but there is totally like Porter
Robinson came to mind when you're when
you're taking say did you see his worlds
tour I didn't I saw him I feel like the
only time I saw him was in Vegas okay so
that was that was more like a party and
I'd say but he oh yeah worlds
but he was playing with someone else it
was when he was he did a tour it was
someone else and they were both on the
stage like Madeon maybe yeah it was like
two guys but yeah but either way like
it's so cool you have these guys like
Odessa and in puerto robinson and
there's so many that they create i mean
cuz cuz you know it can all be measured
like frequency
Hertz all these things like music is all
it hits a different emotions you know
like when I'm speaking when when you
hear people like chanting or in the home
or the or the different chants they hit
like different areas in your body the
chakras of your body the energy centers
of your body and I don't know if you can
get over like both smiling even talking
get the if you are open if you're open
to experiencing it you know this is
something that like an outsider who has
never been to a rave or an outsider who
has been to a rave but they only went to
get [__] up like they yeah you know
they they only went to electronic show
because it was a chance to do Molly or
it's a chance to party and get drunk or
see chicks and in thongs or whatever it
is that people go through definitely
take some thongs yeah I mean that's why
I guess but it's if you go with the open
mindset of it you can seriously
experiencing something like I don't know
where else you can search Church you can
experience it like that but otherwise
it's like you don't get that feeling
it's so weird though does the show I was
talking about I saw what the wall knew
and I I posted Odessa felt like Church
and that was like my caption because I
brought my friend Ashley and she had she
loves Odessa but she had never seen him
I remember being in the car like we're
in the parking garage on like because I
had already seen the tour in New York I
had bought like another ticket and I was
like I don't know how to start this to
you like it's a journey like they're
literally gonna take you on a journey
and she was just mind-blowing she's like
I've never been to something like that
just like the way they make you feel you
can literally feel emotion through
artists like it's so crazy and then just
like the guy like you're saying the
lights the visuals just everything that
they put together is so incredible yeah
it's very profound I was listening to an
interview there's an interview clip I
took it from a sample and I was like
John Lennon or something he was it's
something from The Doors essentially
they were talking about like the future
of music like it'll be one person
perhaps like with different tape tape
recorders and he's playing all the music
and and all these things this is back in
the days of bands and when they're when
we're still just writing music that way
and then years later you have electronic
music store
come up and then you have DJs and VJs
are controlling all the thing and the
world of electronic music I feel like a
lot of people who don't listen to it
don't realize how intricate and how
in-depth how far people have explored
down the sound like tunnel when it comes
to when it comes to this stuff like
these people are doing incredible stuff
and the technology keeps improving like
I am I haven't fully figured it out but
I'm fairly able to run my own lights
while I DJ now like live it's it's kind
of hard like and this is without having
a whole separate like light setup like I
can do it and have someone next to me
and run lights but everything is getting
more connected in that world and so do
the next you know five ten years with I
don't know if we're gonna add virtual
reality or what the hell we're gonna add
on stages but it's gonna be crazy as
[__] I can't wait to see it it's gonna
be awesome
what's the what's the just whatever pops
into mind if you can think of anything
what's like the craziest [__] you've
seen it concerts like I was think about
like the giant owl at Travis Scott that
was so wow that was just so big Justin
Bieber his purpose tour had this crazy
like LED light cage it was like
something I'd never seen before I'm so
one to her I didn't go to it
it was so [__] good it was so great I
don't honestly I've I don't know I've
seen a lot of artists like lift up off
the stage you know what I mean like in
general things have you ever seen where
they lift up and they like float above
the crowd yeah so I saw the Taylor Swift
and she did that and she like has
acoustic guitar and she was doing that
I've seen a lot of stuff like that um I
I know what you're talking about with
the Travis cute because I saw him twice
during that to her I don't know what's
the craziest thing I've seen honestly
like an object not visuals like a yeah I
mean any of it really but I feel like an
object is what pop into my mind just cuz
it's so quick like they somebody designs
that giant object and like now we got to
travel around right I honestly sorry
podcast I have a blank on this window
drawn a blank okay I have a great
replacement for that okay tell me about
mmm that goth law Oh paint this picture
for the listeners because I feel like
when you told me yeah I might've texted
you a couple days afterwards or we
talked or snapchatted or something
oh my gosh so I went to gov ball which
is a festival in New York I feel like a
lot of people here probably wouldn't
know about it but which okay but my
listeners aren't just here that I have I
hope one of you have been to gumball
okay so it's a great festival but it was
like I don't know if it was all ages or
if it was 18 plus but there are a lot of
young kids just like not there for the
music let's put it that way just like I
remember I was sitting trying
I was watching Damian Marley and this
girl this girl's so hammered I'm not 21
can you buy me a blue moon it was just
like constant if they saw you how to
wristband like it was so many young kids
that is that's a weird feeling yeah yeah
it was a lot of people weren't there for
the music and they were just I mean I've
been trashed at a festival obvious but
I'm talking trash you know when you're
young and like can't hold your alcohol
and you're excited and you're at a
festival like it was just kids falling
all over yeah just a lot it was like me
a Tresckow 18 so it was a lot of that I
went with Lauren was like man I loved
the lineup but I don't think I could go
again just because the crowd there
people can suck but the the setup was
great they had all these different like
food vendors from New York just it was
really cool like their art and they just
had different bar areas it was really
cool but I want to say it was the last
day and I mean if you've ever been to a
festival by the third day you're like
you're tired you're still going at it
but you're like I'm tired like you've
been going for like 15 hours straight
host and your feet hurt and I remember
we were at the sticky lebar and we're
sitting there having margarita and
Eminem was gonna play and I as a group
were like okay we'll just go check him
out for a little bit you know we're just
that tired and so that ended up being
the best
of the whole festival so it's pouring
down rain and everyone he's playing all
of his old songs like everyone just seen
dancing and then brings out [__] 50
cent my mouth just dropped I remember I
was like see that come yeah it was
awesome he brought out another rapper
too but I think he was like a local New
York guy um but even he brought out 50
cent oh my god like I just like it was
what track do they do you remember what
do you rember what track they did they
did in the club it's asked like that or
is that Nate Dogg should you smell it
ass like that I don't know no they think
they did like three tracks um you know
in the club I want to say what's the
Simon's like go short it is [__] I think
it's not kosher I don't even want to
know what videos I can look back at and
then I know he's saying baby baby baby
baby oh yeah millionaire whatever yeah
well I'm so not on my rap game right now
but yeah so it was just the whole setup
was so cool like the whole crowd -
really made it because it's pouring down
rain all of us are soaked
it's the lot like this is closing out
the festival right you know you've had
this great weekend and we almost didn't
go it was so crazy and then it ended up
being the coolest thing ever
and Eminem did great all the old tracks
like it was just such a throwback show
isn't it crazy like how because we've
probably been to multigon to multiple
festivals where like that's been the
case where it starts raining and you'd
think there is like a little bit of the
initial like oh [__] but then within two
minutes everybody is like like it's
raining that's we're still doing the
thing and then it all of a sudden turns
into almost like more of a party mode
sometimes yeah I feel like it does yeah
dude I'm trying to think
like it seems like tip my tongue maybe
Diplo or something I've been - I've been
to another like one that got Wow because
it rained yeah I I don't get upset at
rain well first of all you're so sweaty
out of show any you know like if you
haven't been to a festival right we're
talking thousands of people crowding to
go to the stage I mean you don't have
room to move like you're just like your
step people sweat or it's all over
you're lifting your arm up in the person
next to you don't know is putting their
armpit into your armpit yeah hugging
each other's armpits it's why you do it
offensive yeah you're comfortable until
I feel I love when it rains like I just
I was so happy that night like I just
like it I feel like a lot of people like
like my hair or something
[__] your hair - music oh yeah like and
you're so sweaty by that point anyway
but now it was definitely a party it was
so fun I feel kind of it was like three
tracks I'm so sorry that I can't
remember I don't expect you to sent ones
I'm like thinking in my head but I'll
have to pull up the videos I do remember
the song disco inferno by 50 cent in the
seventh grade I dance with that with a
couple homies talent show you know we
definitely snuck that past the principal
you didn't know that song was coming for
show
okay wait and then cuz I didn't know you
in middle school but we met on MySpace
we met on myspace - you do you remember
this yes because it was we started
chatting on MySpace before cuz you went
to Huntington I went to countyman and I
remember it was like Gunnar and a bunch
of people I felt like we all added each
other from Kelly and Kelly Minh and we
all didn't know each other and then we
all became friends
that was the dynamic Soquel so high
school re on because our graduating
class was pretty phat I think I was like
around four or five hundred there was
like quite a few people but so when you
when we went into ninth grade was it did
we go to the year that like the eighth
graders also came with us or something
or ninth graders came up I think so I
know what you're talking about they made
that switch yeah they made the switch
because he used to only be like 10th
11th and 12th grade in high school yeah
but they made in ninth grade but anyway
so there's essentially two big middle
schools and that
kind of a thing like the two middle
schools finally they like converge yeah
it's like this first like meshing when
you like me and everybody in social
media that was the thing like social
media was still new but it was I think
that was definitely the thing where it's
like you go home and you look them up
you try to see if they have a myspace
yet that's where I think you're probably
my top a I feel like you probably work
oh no I was yeah sure
we were yeah well you so like talked a
lot on there I don't know what about
like well we saw each other notes - yeah
we're we are kind of email like Jane of
email okay we were definitely I started
ninth grade with I think I started ninth
grade with half black half pink hair at
one point you had like three colors it
was like white black and then he wore
this really cool red eyeliner yeah yeah
I've been a reppin yeah I've been
getting threatened to get beat up since
day one so I am yeah I remember my mom
really wanted me to shop at Hollister
and stuff she wanted like same I'm
wearing like all black right now but my
family is like you need more color like
you don't wear any color I remember I
just bought everything from like zoomies
and packed Sun and like all those stars
in it with like Hot Topic but was all
black stuff like I remember we would
wear a lot of black too because we would
shop like me and my buddies me and
Gunnar we would go to like Warped Tour
we'd go clothes shopping and warped it
like we wouldn't it's like where would
get our band shirts yeah in the felt so
cool like having it having a band shirt
in high school you're like I'm [__]
cool I was there well it's so crazy now
because I feel like I mean I dress up
sometimes but I just moved houses so I
was like moving all my clothes in my new
house and like most of them are
literally just like been t-shirts right
yeah and I'm like oh this is like a
majority of my closet like I should
probably buy a more color and I should
probably buy some different stuff I
don't know though I think the random
conversations I get into because of my
clothes have always seemed to prove
worthwhile so like if I'm wearing like
I've had a conversation about puia who's
rapper puia there's not a lot of people
who like listen to - like that that side
of rap and I have one of his tour shirts
and that's sparked conversations more
than once I think yeah it's just like
you kind of like band t-shirts are cool
because they pick out people in the
crowd
whoo you're like oh wait you like that
person and sometimes they could even
create this barrier that drops down and
the person doesn't feel afraid to just
completely walk up to you like hey I
like that band a lot too I like your
shirt
I was like I was like that's cool yeah
it's also like created friendships it's
crazy because I remember last year I
wore an odessa sweatshirt to the
triangle I went out one night and it was
like three people I never would have
expected they're like oh my gosh I saw
them live like I went to Seattle and saw
this tour or I wore like a Rufus shirt
to the star and someone came up to me
we're like oh my gosh I love Rufus you
know so I'm seeing them at Red Rocks oh
yeah this summer and Red Rocks as I was
like been on my bucket list for years
and I actually have like a note in my
phone I'm so easy with like I have a
list of like bucket list stuff I want to
do some cheese you know and I have a lot
of lists and notes how do you hit the
dart to the target if you don't create a
target McKenzie yeah I yeah I like to
write a lot but I made this list and I
was looking at like things like Burning
Man
you know I have different things on
there I want to do Great Wall of China
I'd love to do that too yeah I want to
go to the end that's like not the
touristy part the part that's like kind
of a band I think you have to walk quite
a bit but yeah the whole thing I mean I
think that I read that I don't know how
accurate this is but I think that I read
that they actually have the bodies like
if you died as they were building the
Great Wall they've been well [__] to
add him to the wall put him in there oh
my god brick around him I think that's
awesome honestly I don't know if that's
turned up but I want to believe it you
know maybe we are faces yeah yeah I was
like looking at this list probably a
couple months ago and Red Rocks is on it
and I'm like I fly for free why have I
not been to Red Rocks like it's
ridiculous that I haven't been yet and
so it was just perfect a couple weeks
ago they posted on Instagram we're going
to our favorite venue and and they I
like before I finish early I'm like I
know they're going to Red Rocks and I
bought a ticket for Wednesday and I and
I have one Thursday night that's not
that surprising
you know I know I'll buy so I know like
without
yeah I went to their show and then I was
like now got to go to another one so I
bought another ticket so yeah it's so
cool but sometimes when it's an artist
that you're obsessed with like last
night Dermot or two nights ago different
that's my third time seeing him and it's
like it's even if they're doing the same
set which is most time they're not but
it's totally different show like there's
so much you're like I didn't notice any
of those things last time because you're
you get so transfixed I love going to
see an artist more than once because I
think you get it like really explore
their set really explore what they're
trying to say
yeah especially like with Brock Hampton
on every tour they have is so different
yes they all the way they put their show
together um they're so they'll have what
would you call that like the backdrop
screen I got a show yeah
they'll play like one tour they played a
couple songs and then they stopped and
played a video of them asking each other
like what because it has multiple
members um so they'll be like what does
sex mean to you they'll ask them just
random questions three of the guys will
answer and they're completely different
you know just stop the show and play
like these random videos let's random
questions and then they'll pick back
again pick up again and then they'll
play a couple songs do something
different and like that's like an
experience too they do different things
they dress different each album is
different entirely that they have so I
think I could see more I was just like I
was just saying like the DJ world like
gets more and more in depth like more
and more things happening on stage more
of an experience just like immersive
Festival we're talking about you can be
cool like it's gonna be cool to see more
of the immersive like concert just like
the night out it's like this immersive
exterior experience not just going to
look at a stage you know yeah it's more
and more Rockhampton I wanted to explain
who they are really quick for any
listeners who don't know so in you
probably already knew this but did you
know that they met on the Kanye to the
forum yeah yes so there is a Kanye West
forum this group Rockhampton Kevin
abstract is kinda like the leader the
head and from my understanding he
essentially posted on Kanye to that and
was like I want to start like a boy band
I want to start group who wants to
[__] move out to LA and join me
and I think it was la say it was it
Santa Monica that's it
no California yeah they moved to LA but
they all lived in Texas I think it's
like Corpus Christi or mmm they lived
somewhere in Texas and they moved to LA
yeah obviously I thought that they
didn't know each other in person before
I thought that it was like a purely
internet I mean up no no it was okay
yeah but then they all move to LA yeah I
think they all live some I want to say
like a couple of them knew each other
but definitely not all of them yeah well
in there like like the people who are on
stage you know there's rappers and
singers like they kind of do everything
they're like the like the song Bohemian
Rhapsody by Queen like every one of
their songs is like that but modern like
it's it like Minh other songs would just
be like slow and beautiful and like
they're just very experimental they're
very cool but they credit their like
their videographers like their producers
like I don't know like they're the other
people are we rock Hampton yeah they're
all brought Campton like they're not
like just the dudes who are on stage
like that's the performers but they
consider their whole group yeah like the
manager the people doing the visual yeah
they just like the producers they
consider them all Brock Hampton how do
you feel about Amir I think I had to
bring it up man okay so this short
controversy Amir was one of the members
of the group and essentially he got like
he was like mistreated a woman like he
did something bad and the internet like
found out about it and the internet was
like he needs to be kicked out of the
band [__] that and they had just signed
my understanding was they just signed
with RCA and in order to keep that
contract it was like RCA was like we
can't deal with the drama of this guy
like he's got to go yeah like he like
said something to me he like treated a
woman battle know if he like beat the
[__] out it wasn't like beating should
have a girl or anything I don't think
but I heard like I don't know what's
true this is an internet you know you
like these could all be I heard the same
thing like it had to do with a woman and
then I also heard that he set up like a
robbery to get like one of us [__] yeah
yeah like one of his friends robbed he
was like behind on it
and then they all found out right I
forgot I think you even told me about
that yeah so I don't but I mean these
are things circling like we don't know
their life we don't know yeah he was
removed from the group and I was just
saying from as a listeners perspective
like dude his flows are hot like he was
such a great contribute contributed to
Brock Hampton in my opinion like what I
did see them
we saw the block party like after he had
been kicked out and after they had kind
of like gotten back on their feet and
they're performing more and it
transformed them yeah like they were
they were more they were more themselves
than I had ever seen them like they came
out you know without without a mirror
like this is by a year later
yeah and man they they had all like
[__] butterflied in different ways
and yeah they were awesome I felt like I
really love their saturation albums with
that which they have like a trilogy in a
mirror is on all of them but their
albums like after that just like really
blew up as well I felt like with all the
drama they just really put their heart
and soul into that next album yeah and
yeah it was great okay give listeners -
Dermott songs to check out and then to
Brockhampton songs check out if they
never heard either of these people okay
so I feel like should I say the songs I
like or that the general population will
like cuz I feel like that's trust your
recommendation I would trust your
recommendations your favorite is
probably fine
I would say without fear but just
letting you guys really slow it has like
a really good build-up and a lot of
emotion but it's not something you go in
listening to like oh like I'm gonna jam
out to the oh yeah this is like you're
sittin thinking about your feelings and
like reminisce it's not your life it's
some winter music that is my favorite
song is without fear
I also so the most popular song is
outnumbered so I feel like people like
that but I also I really like all my
friends yeah that's a really good one
yeah on it and that's a little more
upbeat for people I'm trying to like
give them something
slow you want to like cry you're gonna
cry your bed listen to this young and
free is kind of its kind of fat well in
power over me I guess is Laurie like
builds up to you know would either way
they don't have to be fast though so so
without fear I'd say without fear and
all my friends I really like they're
both like different I guess
and that's Dermot Kenny this de RM o T
Kennedy you can get him on [__]
anywhere he's a fantastic artist we just
saw him so and what about Brock Hampton
give me two for them Brock Camden um for
a slower one I really like Tanya and
that was up yeah that they each get on
and they're really raw about their
feelings like it's kind of like the slow
rap but it's like if you listen to the
lyrics like they're all going through
some [__] and they all just bring it to
the table um for yeah so for like a
slower Chuck and gummy gummy yeah gummy
definitely that song gets me hyped like
I'll turn that up in my car and I can
rap most of it
so it's the [__] yeah I really like that
song so I'd recommend that those though
I feel like the song is I'm saying
though they're not if you go Spotify
they're not on their top five so still
yeah still listen to those songs but I
feel like Brock Hampton is definitely an
artist because I I think was saturating
to when I got into them and but it gives
the point where you can kind of like
their stuff is so different like all of
their songs are so different so like you
can really explore in depths of like
it's like oh there's their older stuff
is is this way or their newer stuff is
this way it's like all of their stuff is
vastly different honestly yeah it's
really good I still listen to the
saturation albums they're great yeah and
yeah like I don't know for people that
don't listen but they are so different
like his mode a lot of artists have the
same kind of rhythm or saying you know
some albums do kind of like have the
same sound but we're talking I mean
these guys are like hardcore rappers and
then there'll be a song with just bare
face which is one of the guys and he's
just like seeing his heart out I thought
yeah about his life and yeah well in the
end they'll sing it's really cool to
even relating back to like the
talking about feelings and talking about
like more more real raw [__] like they
like like that whole situation where
they had one of their like closest
friends their band members like turn
their back on you know whatever happened
they had to kick him out of the group
like they would go out on stage and like
just literally talk about those feelings
and like you can see young kids in the
crowd bawling for sure like the the
connection that so many young people
have to the artists on stage is is huge
anyway and it's so cool to have artists
that are like no we're gonna talk about
real [__] like yeah maybe this isn't
gonna get us the number it's like maybe
this isn't like for the party but this
is like I don't know man it's pretty
grueling to have to dig into the depths
of your soul to write something that
makes you cry and then try to perform it
on stage for a bunch of people yeah one
thing I really like about them I feel
there's a lot of different types of rap
so I'm not saying there's one kind but
you know like from what my perspective
and things I've realized like top forty
you know ass titties like you know like
it's all rapping you know party like you
listen to these songs when you're
partying listen these songs at the club
like these guys are hardcore rapping but
they're literally talking about their
feelings like it's not they're not like
yeah I'm gonna slay [__] tonight and
you know it's not stuff like that like
they are talking just about stuff you
can absolutely relate to and so that's
why I love having people on the fringes
like Kevin Hart he's a gay black rapper
he's actually he's a gay black grabber
and he talks about that like I mean I
couldn't imagine like that the
tribulation that he's probably gone
through yeah being a gay black rapper
yeah even things like that bringing that
to the surface it's just so cool but
actually making it enjoyable to listen
to you like I'm a white dude from Kelso
and I just enjoy the [__] out of the
music yeah yeah I think that's awesome
that he can bring that to that because
yeah I mean I guess it's more common now
but if you think about it like it was
probably really hard for like there
aren't a lot of like open gay black
rappers I feel like like I feel more now
but when they start
it was probably like he's like all right
like I just got a he was not scared to
be who he was and just put it all out on
the table well it has an artist when you
do that it gives permission to everybody
I use his reference on the podcasts all
the time when travis Pastrana first did
on a motorcycle when he first did a
backflip within just a few weeks there
was multiple people doing backflips yeah
you give people permission like he gets
up there and he says hey here's who I am
that's ok I'm gonna talk about it
because there's people who want to
listen to it you know and now there's
young kids there's other people you know
they're fans who now have permission to
be fully themselves like in whatever
version they are I love it yeah it's
like one of those things like alright my
idol they're talking about it like like
weird we touched on this earlier like
I'm not the only one feeling this way so
and I think that's really a great aspect
about music too like you can relate I
relate to so many different lyrics it
doesn't matter if it's rap it doesn't
matter if it's like acoustic guitar like
it's just crazy how much you can relate
yeah we are getting that the I was
trying I was gonna wrap it up here I was
trying to know I want to be respectful
of your time here so we will wrap it up
so let's end it with this I was trying
to fabricate this question so maybe you
can help me I was thinking oh gosh is it
going to be hard it was gonna be sick
aliens they come down to earth right
this is it we're going with this aliens
coming down to earth
you've traveled to quite a few places by
now okay they they if you were in charge
of the location that they come to
because they're like we gotta check out
our like we got like what's you got to
show them that earth is pretty you got
to show them that Earth is awesome
earth is like don't don't kill us earth
is great see you got a show on that
where you gonna have these aliens go
because I haven't been everywhere so I
don't know I the first thing was Iceland
I said like or Thailand I know yeah
because I haven't I've been to a lot of
gear up and stuff but yeah cuz I'd say
Iceland I just I love it so much it has
everything it's so beautiful but that's
my perspective where would you have them
go
I mean I what's funny is instantly I
thought of Tokyo but I think I was just
being selfish because that's where I
want to go I just want to go hang out
there but I'm an alien because yeah I
thought of like a big city do they want
us because well you said no they did see
culture I take them to West world to the
west come to the west world where they
could do anything with the robots for
anyone who hasn't watched West world oh
yeah the show is wild I think maybe
those aliens yeah we talked about this
earlier yeah anybody who hasn't seen
that show you need to yeah like
definitely top 5 my favorite show Savage
is the ingenious the intro just like
calms your heart it's beautiful visually
and hearing lies what I keep saying
hearing wise ok I've messed up a couple
times
alright like just as honed out that's
how it happens well with the podcast you
realize that like oh like people don't
let me talk for this long like I didn't
realize like am I good to keep going
yeah I was like for you guys who haven't
been in Jake's basement it's awesome
like there's so much there's a wall with
like all these quotes and writing and
it's really easy to get not lost but
yeah I lost him here um I was reading
everything and just like taking
everything in earlier so yeah I feel
like I'm like looking around and I'm
like oh yeah okay yeah I need to focus
no that's good it's my little ADHD
chamber it's it's it's cool I've gotten
of course I love it but everybody who's
come down here for the podcasts or
musicians I'm working on have just been
like wow it's incredible I get it like
it's a it's you know what I wanted to be
is like a portal to like like a if you
could come here and you feel like you
can grab your most your most
inspirational side of yourself if you
feel like you can like connect to like
your most artistic self the most you the
most like part the the most part of you
the part of knew that most loves
yourself I want that to be activated
here and in this portal you know and
it's so great it's so there's so much
positivity and yeah just all the coats
on the wall or just keep going you know
yeah maybe that's that's what I'll have
if aliens come down you come on down the
junkyard love ya I'll show you the black
hey what's a human brain like and I'm
like
the wall yeah I'm fair now I'm trying
yeah and I'll try to decipher everything
yeah it is funny because how soul raw
okay come to Castle Rock Washington will
show you around aliens I had I had Jay
over here the other day and she and
she's like wow it's incredible to be
inside your mind here
then should I looked around I was like
yeah it is kind of like my mind just
splattered everywhere yeah I feel like
yeah it definitely feels like home like
you could bring her I could bring my
journal here and just sit crisscross on
the floor and probably right please do
next time you're in town if you need a
day to just get away all I can put some
headphones on and work on my [__] and
come to find out yeah well thank you so
much yeah because it's so grand a lot
you didn't ramble at all no need to
apologize I'm glad I had you on here I
just kind of like I texted yesterday and
I was like hey you want to be on a
podcast cuz you're in town so I kind of
caught you off guard so I do appreciate
you coming here and sharing a little bit
of your story I want to let you know
that I appreciate you appreciate your
friendship appreciate all the years that
we've been friends I hope we have many
more years of friendship grown it to be
a wonderful wonderful beautiful
inspiring woman and I'm glad that my
friend oh thank you
same to you oh my god sorry it's gonna
get almost shown we're gonna cry often
same way about you thank you so much all
right it's been great listeners have a
good rest of your day drink some water
take care of yourself and next time you
see a stranger look him in the eyes and
smile bye guys
you